Heezen-Tharp collection: Pacific Ocean
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress
- Series II: Pacific Ocean Special Projects
  - Group 30 - Pacific Ocean Special Projects Worksheets, 17691486
    - A0003 Worksheets for Glomar 6 (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Positive print. b. From 30˚ to 31˚ North and 146˚ to 150˚ East. Soundings.
    - A0004 Worksheets for Glomar 6 (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Positive print. b. From 146˚ to 150˚ East. Soundings.
    - A0005 Worksheets for Glomar 6 (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Positive print. b. From 146˚ to 150˚ East. Select Soundings, 7 September 1971.
    - A0006 Worksheets for Glomar 6 (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Positive print. b. From 146˚ to 150˚ East. Select Soundings.
    - A0007 [Anomalies Orientation Sheet] (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Tracing paper. b. Intersection of rift valley and equator. Pencil copy.
    - A0008 [Fracture Segments] (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Paper. b. From 60˚ North to 60˚ South and 60˚ West to 120˚ East. Master sheet of numbered fracture segments.
    - A0009 [Cores] (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Paper. b. Covers Pacific Ocean, cores plotted on Pacific Ocean Floor Map. Some include column data.
    - A0010 [Tracks] (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Tracing paper. b. From 20˚ to 40˚ North near Midway. Colored pencil copy.
    - A0011 [Contours] (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Tracing paper. b. From 23˚ to 30˚ North and 170˚ to 179˚ East. Pencil copy.
    - A0012 [Drill Sites in Northern Pacific] (Folder Barcode: 0027567784A)
      a. Paper. b. From 30˚ North to 40˚ South and 110˚ East to 150˚ West. Plotted on Physiographic Map of the Western Pacific Ocean. Some color-coded data.
  - Group 31 - Pacific Ocean Special Projects Publications, 17691431
    - A0001 [Geologic Periods for the Northern Pacific Ocean] (Folder Barcode: 00275677838)
      a. Negative print. b. Covers area from equator north. Ready for publication.
    - A0002 [Geologic Periods for the Northern Pacific Ocean] (Folder Barcode: 00275677838)
      a. Positive print. b. Covers area from equator north. Ready for publication.
    - A0003 [Complete Graphic of A0001 and A0002 Showing Water Depths and Cores] (Folder Barcode: 00275677838)
      a. Paper. b. Covers cores 44-60, water depths for sites 44-51 and A0001 map.
  - Group 32 - Pacific Ocean Special Projects Miscellaneous, 17691574
    2 items
    - A0001 [Unidentified Data] (Folder Barcode: 00275677826)
      a. Negative prints. b. According to Marie Tharp, this could be data showing the depth of the bedrock related to the Glomar Challenger cruises. Strip of frames 1158-1171.
    - A0002 [Unidentified Data] (Folder Barcode: 00275677826)
      a. Negative prints. b. According to Marie Tharp, this could be data showing the depth of the bedrock related to the Glomar Challenger cruises.
- Series III: Pacific Ocean Geologic Map
  - Group 33 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Cores, 17691650
    - B0001 Deep Sea Drilling and Coring Table (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Paper. b. Key to map symbols. Cut from larger map.
    - B0002 DSDP Lithologies (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Key to map symbols.
    - B0003 DSDP Holes (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. No other identification information.
    - B0004 Sediment Cores and Opaque Layer Thickness (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Paper. b. From 60˚ North to 10˚ South and 80˚ West to 120˚ East. Shows geologic ages and thicknesses in meters.
    - B0005 Eocene and Younger Cores (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 40˚ West to 40˚ East. Piston cores and dredges.
    - B0006 Eocene and Younger Cores (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Ozalid. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 40˚ West to 40˚ East. Color-coded and annotated version of B0005.
    - B0007 Cores and Manganese Nodules (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Color-coded cores. Marked obsolete.
    - B0008 DSDP Columns (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Red negative transparency. b. Publication master.
    - B0009 DSDP Columns-Ages (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Ozalid. b. Colored version.
    - B0010 DSDP Holes-Lithologies (Folder Barcode: 00275677814)
      a. Ozalid. b. Black-and-white.
  - Group 34 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Geology, 17691644
    - B0001 [Geologic Ages] (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Paper. b. Colored blocks plotted on National Geographic Society Pacific Ocean Floor map, October 1969.
    - B0002 Sediment Thickness (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil and ink. Draft.
    - B0003 Russian Sediments (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Ink with pencil annotations. Draft.
    - B0004 Russian Sediments (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 40˚ East to 40˚ West. Color- coded with key.
    - B0005 Fractures (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 40˚ East to 40˚ West.
    - B0006 Fractures and 1st Motion Arrows (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Sea of Japan, deep focus.
    - B0007 1st Motion Arrows (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil and ink. Includes key.
    - B0008 Age Boundary (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Marked Final. Pencil version.
    - B0009 Seamounts (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Ozalid. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 70˚ East to 40˚ West. Color- coded by geologic age
    - B0010 Active Volcanos and Guyots (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Ozalid. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 90˚ East to 110˚ West. Also includes some reefs and atolls.
    - B0011 Faults Plate (Folder Barcode: 00275677802)
      a. Ozalid. b. Identifies sources of boundary plate data.
  - Group 35 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Earthquakes, 17691616
    - B0001 Earthquakes (Folder Barcode: 00275677796)
      a. Ozafoil b. Red separation.
    - B0002 Earthquake Epicenters- Pacific (Folder Barcode: 00275677796)
      a. Ozalid. b. World-wide. Also has geologic blocks drawn in red.
  - Group 36 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Magnetism, 17691610
    - B0001 Magnetics and Faults (Folder Barcode: 00275677784)
      a. Tracing paper. b. From 70˚ to 180˚ East. Covers the Macquarie Ridge Complex. Hand-colored. From Weissel and Hayes, 1972.
    - B0002 Obsolete Magnetics (Folder Barcode: 00275677784)
      a. Tracing paper. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 110˚ East to 40˚ West. Clean inked version.
    - B0003 [Pacific Magnetics Overlay] (Folder Barcode: 00275677784)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. From 60˚ North to 60˚ South and 120˚ East to 70˚ West. Pencil and ink.
  - Group 37 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Bathymetry, 17691600
    - B0001 Bathymetry Corrections and New Bathymetry (Folder Barcode: 00275677772)
      a. Paper. b. Colored copy of base map showing new bathymetry and suggested corrections for final copy.
    - B0002 Bathymetric Plate (Folder Barcode: 00275677772)
      a. Paper. b. Shows work and printing instructions on collar.
    - B0003 Bathymetry (Folder Barcode: 00275677772)
      a. Ozafoil b. Copy of final base map.
  - Group 38 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Contours, 17691768
    4 items
    - B0001 Final Isopachs (Folder Barcode: 00275677760)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Inked version, sheet #4.
    - B0002 Isopachs (Folder Barcode: 00275677760)
      a. Ozafoil. b. Blue Mylar version of B0001.
    - B0003 Isopachs from Mylar Trace (Folder Barcode: 00275677760)
      a. Paper. b. Hand-colored Pacific contours with edit instructions.
    - B0004 Isopachs Including North America (Folder Barcode: 00275677760)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Blue plate.
  - Group 39 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Worksheets, 17691763
    13 items
    - B0001 [Contour Worksheet] (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Tracing paper. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 90˚ East to 90˚ West.
    - B0002 [40% Tint Layer] (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
    - B0003 Opaque Layer - Horizon A (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
    - B0004 [Fractures and Magnetics] (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Ozalid. b. From 40˚ North to 40˚ South and 80˚ East to 40˚ West.
    - B0005 Final Age Boundaries (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Ozalid. b. Color-coded version.
    - B0006 Abyssal Plains and Canyons (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
    - B0007 [Pacific Overlay] (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
    - B0008 [Pacific Overlay] (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Mostly pencil. No other identification information.
    - B0009 Pacific Map Ideas for Corrections (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. At 39˚ 40' South and 175˚ 30' West.
    - B0010 Opaque Layer-Additions (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Includes a yellow lined- paper overlay that is taped on with masking tape.
    - B0011 Final Corrections Sheet for Pacific Drill Columns (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil copy.
    - B0012 Corrections to Age Boundaries (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pencil copy to be scribed.
    - B0013 Fracture Zones - Corrections (Folder Barcode: 00275677759)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Pacific map correction sheet for faults. Pencil copy.
  - Group 40 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Photographs, 17691743
    1 item
    - B0001 Sea Cliff, a. Paper print. b. Photograph of diving submersible. (Folder Barcode: 00275677747)
      a. Paper print. b. Photograph of diving submersible.
  - Group 41 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Publications, 17691779
    5 items
    - B0001 [Overlay] (Folder Barcode: 00275677735)
      a. Mylar. b. Symbols overlay for published map. No other information.
    - B0002 Lettering for Geologic Map (Folder Barcode: 00275677735)
      a. Tracing paper. b. Hand lettered with pencil. Shows Island Groups, Fracture Zones, Ridges and Seamount Chains. Sheet # 12-Grey.
    - B0003 Letter Symbols for Ages (Folder Barcode: 00275677735)
      a. Tracing paper. b. Hand lettered with pencil. Sheet # 13-Black.
    - B0004 Anomalies (Folder Barcode: 00275677735)
      a. Ozafoil. b. Series of numbered parallel lines.
    - B0005 Anomalies (Folder Barcode: 00275677735)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Series of final numbers. Sheet #5-Gray.
  - Group 42 - Pacific Ocean Geologic Map Published Maps, 17691775
    6 items
    - B0001 Colors Sheet (Folder Barcode: 00275677723)
      a. Paper. b. Y-0, 10, 25, 45, 70, and Y- 100.
    - B0002 [Geologic Areas Highlighted on the National Geographic Map of the Pacific Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275677723)
      a. Paper. b. Published by National Geographic in October 1969. Map is based on Heezen and Tharp data and painted by Heinrich Berann
    - B0003 Base Map (Folder Barcode: 00275677723)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Black plate for Geologic Map of the Pacific.
    - B0004 Base Map (Folder Barcode: 00275677723)
      a. Paper. b. Printing proof of black plate for Geologic Map of the Pacific. Item B0003.
    - B0005 Geologic Map of the Pacific Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275677723)
      a. Frosted acetate. b. Black-and-white copy of final map. Items B0003 and 0004.
    - B0006 final Proof of Geologic Map of the Pacific Ocean (Folder Barcode: 00275677723)
      a. Cromalin paper. b. Hand-colored version of final map. Items B0003, 0004, and 0005.
- Series IV: Pacific Ocean Boxed Materials
  Groups 43 - 45
  - Group 43 - Pacific Ocean Boxed Materials Processed Profiles, 18458178
    10 boxes; estimated 500 items
    - Box 1 (Box 00212681179)
    - Box 2 (Box 00212681209)
    - Box 3 (Box 00212681180)
    - Box 4 (Box 00212681210)
    - Box 5 (Box 00212681222)
    - Box 6 (Box 00212681234)
    - Box 7 (Box 00212681246)
    - Box 8 (Box 00212681258)
    - Box 9 (Box 0021268126A)
    - Box 10 Oversized (Box 00212682986)
  - Group 44 - Pacific Ocean Boxed Materials Profile Sheets by Sections, 18459847
    5 boxes; estimated 250
    - Box 1 (Box 00212681131)
    - Box 2 (Box 00212681192)
    - Box 3 (Box 00212681192)
    - Box 4 (Box 00212681192)
    - Box 5 (Box 00212681192)
  - Group 45 - Pacific Ocean Boxed Materials Unprocessed Profiles, 18457988
    4 boxes; estimated 200 items
    - Box 1 (Box 0021268157A)
    - Box 2 (Box 00212681581)
    - Box 3 (Box 00212681593)
    - Box 4 (Box 0021268160A)